Reverend Master, in your compassion and
Kính bạch quý ngài Nương lòng từ bi và
guidance, Master Thich Truc Thai Minh and the monks of
sự chỉ dạy trên sư phụ cùng Chư tăng
Ba Vang Pagoda, every year, the Buddhist followers of the
chùa Ba Vàng hàng năm phật tử thuộc câu
Golden Chrysanthemum Club, practicing the Six Harmonies,
lạc bộ Cúc Vàng tập tu Lục Hòa của chúng
participate in the three-month retreat
con đều được tu tập theo ba tháng an cư
of the monks. This is to deepen our understanding of Right View,
của Chư tăng Để thâm nhập Chánh kiến
increase our wisdom, cultivate virtue, and increase our
tăng trưởng trí tuệ tu bồi giới Đức tăng
blessings. The three months of the rainy season, during the rainy season
trưởng phúc lành ba tháng mùa mưa là
retreat, are
thời gian chưa tăng vào mùa an cư kiết
dedicated to studying and
hạ để dành thời gian cho việc tu học
cultivating virtue, and this
thuộc liếm thân tâm trau dồi Đức đây
is also an opportunity for lay Buddhists to
cũng là cơ hội cho hàng Phật tử tại gia
cultivate merit through
phát tâm gieo trồng ruộng Phước qua việc
supporting the Three Jewels and diligently practicing. With the
hộ Trì Tam Bảo tinh tấn tu tập được sự
permission of Master Thich Truc
cho phép của trường sư phụ Thích Trúc
Thai Minh and the monks of Ba Vang Pagoda, on the
Thái Minh cùng Chư tăng chùa Ba Vàng
3rd day of the 5th lunar month of the Year of the Rabbit (
ngày mùng 3 tháng 5 năm Quý Mão tức ngày
June 20, 2023), Ms. Pham
20 tháng 6 năm 2023 cô chủ nhiệm Phạm
Thi Yen, the club's leader, along with representatives of the Buddhist followers of the
Thị Yến cùng đại diện các phật tử trong
Golden Chrysanthemum Club,
câu lạc bộ Cúc Vàng tập thơ Lục Hòa tại
participated in the three-month retreat
chùa đã tang tu tập theo 3 tháng an cư
of the monks at the pagoda. Simultaneously, throughout the provinces and
của Chư tăng Đồng thời tại khắp các tỉnh
cities, members of the Golden Chrysanthemum Club
thành các phân tử trong câu lạc bộ Cúc
have also begun
Vàng tập tô Lục Hòa đã hướng tâm khai
their practice in the three-month retreat.  The monks
đàn tu tập theo ba tháng an cư kiết hạ
' summer retreat was conducted online,
của Chư tăng thông qua mạng trực tuyến
during which Buddhists collectively
theo đó các phật tử đã cùng nhau phát
vowed to practice chanting sutras, repenting, meditating,
nguyện tu tập tụng kinh sám hối Thiền
performing good deeds, encouraging each
Quán làm các việc phước thiện sách tấn
other to increase merit, cultivate the Six Harmonies,
nhau tăng trưởng Công Đức Lục Hòa khai
open wisdom, and guide our fellow practitioners.
mở trí tuệ và các quỹ đạo hữu chúng ta
During these three months of practice, we turn our
trong 3 tháng tu tập này chúng ta xoay
minds inward, repent, and examine our own
tâm vào chúng ta sám hối chúng ta nhìn
minds to liberate ourselves from all
nhận tâm mình giải thoát khỏi tất cả các
unwholesome thoughts. We should constantly contemplate
bất thiện tâm hãy thường quán chiếu tâm
our minds to free ourselves from them, and practice self-
mình để giải thoát khỏi nó hãy tự sám
repentance extensively. When we
hối là nhiều Còn khi nào thấy mình thực
truly feel a good heart, joy, and clarity,
sự có thiện tâm có hoan hỷ có sáng suốt
then we should point out faults; otherwise, we should refrain from pointing out faults.
thì hãy chỉ lỗi không thì đừng chỉ lỗi
During the three months of the monks' summer retreat, we
trong 3 tháng an cư kiết hạ của Chư tăng
hope that Buddhists will diligently cultivate compassion
mong rằng các phật tử sẽ tinh tấn tu tập
to spread the
tầm từ bi để cùng lan tỏa nguồn năng
energy of good hearts, dedicating it to the
lượng Thiện Tâm hồi hướng cho đất nước
peaceful and happy nation and its people.
Thái Bình nhân dân được bình an hạnh
[Music]
[âm nhạc]